Kunal Kolhe





Marunji, Hinjewadi Phase I, Pune – 411057



SUMMARY

Result oriented individual having statistical and analytical ability with 2.4 years of industry experience in software development, data science with data processing, data mining, data modelling, data visualizations, data insights, and machine learning techniques to meet business needs. Motivated to learn, grow, and excel my experience with challenging myself.

KEY SKILLS

Programing Languages - Python, OOP's with C++, Data Structure, R, Java, HTML, CSS, Qt-QML

Machine/ Deep Learning Libraries - Pandas, Numpy, Scikit-learn, Pycaret, Keras, TensorFlow, Statsmodels, BeautifulSoup Data Visualizations - Matplotlib, Seaborn, Plotly, Tableau

Database Technologies/ Big Data Frameworks - MySQL, NoSQL, Spark, PySpark, Hadoop, MapReduce

Natural Language Processing Libraries - NLTK, TextBlob, Spacy, FastText, Gensim

Web Frameworks/ Cloud Services - Flask, Django, Streamlit, API

IDE/ Platforms - Jupyter Notebook, PyCharm, Spider, Sublime Text, R Studio, Eclipse, Google Colab, Kaggle Kernel

WORK EXPERIENCE

Innodatatics Inc. - USA, Branch Office: Hydrabad

Data Scientist Intern - (Nov. 2020 – Feb. 2021)

- Building predictive and decision models using machine learning algorithms for various business study cases with optimizations and evaluation techniques.
- Analyzed large and imbalanced datasets by performing machine learning techniques to provide data insights, optimistic solutions and strategic directions for making data driven decisions.
- Developed customized scripts for scraping the data from multiple websites.
- Worked with text data with text mining techniques including text extraction, cleaning, pattern identifications, categorizations, and entity recognitions.
- End-to-end deployment of ML and NLP solutions on web-based frameworks like heroku, flask, Django.

KPIT Technologies - Rajiv Gandhi Infotech Park, Pune

Software Engineer - (Jan. 2019 – Jan. 2021)

- Collaborated on all the stages of software development life cycle from the requirements gathering to the production releases as per client specifications.
- Analysis of all data strategies, its constrains and deliver the reports for clients.
- Closely worked with analyst and internal research teams to translate business requirements into technical solutions with attending client calls, project meetings and discussion with process consultant and architect.
- HMI integration with development for Head Up Display cluster and infotainment system using C++, Python, Qt-QML with object-oriented approach.

Software Trainee - (Oct. 2018 – Dec. 2018)

- Maintained highest levels of development practices including technical design, solution development, test documentation, issue identification and resolution.
- Developed internal solutions with python scripts that automate the business processes and created image verification tool.

CERTIFICATIONS

- Certificate Program in Data Science using Machine Learning with R and Python (IBM)
- Text Analytics Certificate (IBM)

EDUCATION

C-DAC Kharghar – New Mumbai (2018 - 2018) PG-DAC in Computer Science (Aggregate 65.70 %)

Data Science Certification (ExcelR)

PARTICIPATIONS

- National workshop on Python with Data Science (DYPIMS, Pune)
- Microsoft Al Classroom Series Program (Microsoft,
- Technical DevFest event (GDG, India)

BATU University – BATU, Lonere, Raigad (2013 - 2017) B-Tech. in Electrical Engineering (CGPA: 6.45)

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Recognized as Crown Developer out of 160 employees.
- Secured gold medal in indoor carrom championship at University level.

PROJECTS

Innodatatics Inc.

Title: Hospital Insurance Fraud Claims Detection (Jan. 2021 – Feb. 2021)

- The objective of project is to detect the fraud claims by Hospitals to the Insurance Company.
- Analyzed and understood each of technical details related to business case, done EDA using Tableau and Python. Explained
 the data insights, outcomes, and experimental findings with teams and lead in meetings and discussions.
- Used random forest classification algorithm, imbalanced dataset having more than 100K records with 24 features with data up sampling technique and achieved model accuracy 87% with F1-score 88%.
- Presented overall model interpretations, reports to senior lead and deployed the model using flask and heroku. [Link]

Title: Text Analytics (Nov. 2020 - Jan. 2021)

- Project aim was to develop text-based model which tells the effectiveness of drugs along with its side effects.
- Collected online customer reviews data 125K from drug websites by developing the web scrappers with the help of selenium and extracted all the text fields.
- Analyzed and performed text processing as duplications, expanding contractions, text cleaning with available methods in NLTK library and implemented FastText for detection of the foreign languages.
- Generated the effectiveness of drugs based on polarity, user reviews, and side effects of the drugs. Shared overall findings, reports, and model interpretations with project team and process lead.
- Worked on streamlit framework and heroku platform for model deployment.

KPIT Technologies

Title: Development of HUD Clusters - (Mar. 2020 – Jan. 2021)

- Project aim was to design and developed the HMI scenes, widget modifications as per the analyzed client requirements.
- Implemented the screen transitions for various developed scenes and build the HMI solutions on Linux platform.
- Worked on customer's change requests and provided technical support to other teams in same domain.
- Implemented the SVN diff in code review process successfully, so that it helps to analyzed and track the code change faster on remote basis than actual review process for the project.

Title: Text Based Application Analysis - (Aug. 2019 - Feb. 2020)

- Worked on text module of document parsing and analysis of the applications with internal research project team.
- Updated the existing application scripts with NLTK library by capturing the text fields, and performed the text mining tasks like data cleaning, pattern matching, text extraction with specified domain fields by business needs.
- Generated the application analysis report by matching the required text fields with database and external source files.

Title: Design and Analysis of Infotainment System - (Oct. 2018 – Jul. 2019)

- A POC based project to analyzed the performance of new integrated framework with application interface for in-vehicle infotainment system.
- Developed automations using python for designing the module screens in which QML components were automatically get selected as per client specifications and screens were generated. This improved the productivity of project by 20%.
- Completed the quality reviews for designs, codes, test plans and documentation methods.

LANGUAGES

INTERESTS

English, Hindi, Marathi.

Carrom, Piano, Dance.